http://www.underthenile.com/pages/privacy-policy

My Cart
Close
Home
»
Privacy & Security
Privacy & Security
PRIVACY POLICY  Thank you for visiting www.underthenile.com ("the Site")! The purpose of this privacy policy is to inform users of the Site as to what information we collect and how and why we use such information.
Disclosure Regarding Collection and Use of Personal Information.
Users may enter personal information about themselves through use of the Site. This policy explains our online information collection and use practices and the choices you can make about the way we use and share such information. Please take the time to read and understand this policy. OUR ONLINE INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE PRACTICES MAY DIFFER FROM OUR PRACTICES REGARDING INFORMATION OBTAINED OFFLINE. IF YOU MAKE USE OF THE SITE, REGISTER WITH THE SITE, REQUEST INFORMATION THAT THE SITE MAY OFFER, PARTICIPATE IN A SURVEY, PURCHASE SOMETHING THROUGH THE SITE, REQUEST A CATALOG, ENTER ANY OF OUR CONTESTS OR PROMOTIONS, OR SUBMIT INFORMATION IN ANY WAY TO OR THROUGH THE SITE YOU ARE AGREEING TO THESE TERMS. THIS POLICY IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE.
Secure processing of credit card information.
The security of your personal information is extremely important to Under the Nile, and we have measures in effect that ensure your information is processed accurately, and securely. Our website uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt your order information, such as your name, address and credit card number, during transmission. Once you begin the checkout process you will be in secure mode and you should see a padlock icon at the top of your browser window. In addition, the beginning of the Under the Nile URL address at the top of your browser should change from “http” to “https.”
Under the Nile is a trusted seller and verified merchant. We display security badges from The Better Business Bureau as well as Authorize.net.
The Information We Collect.
In using our site we may collect personal information about you (i.e. information that can directly identify you or indicate where you might be contacted including: name, address, age, date of birth, sex, grade level, email address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services) through the information you provide, other documents that you submit to us, or transactions in which you may engage with us or our affiliated companies. This policy applies to all personal information that we collect and maintain about our users, including any contact information (e.g., name and address), financial information (e.g., account and credit history), or identifying information (e.g., social security number and date of birth) that we may obtain in connection with providing services.
Sometimes you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to a friend, you might submit the friend's name and address. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected about other people at these pages may include: recipient's name, address, age, date of birth, grade level, email address, sex, and telephone number.
Other Collected Information.
We also may collect certain non-personal information (i.e. generic information that does not identify you personally) when you visit any of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows '98 or Mac OS), the IP address you are using to connect to the Site, or the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., America Online or EarthLink).
How We Use Your Personal Information.
We will use the personal information you provide online for the purpose(s) you have submitted (e.g., fulfilling a catalog request, notifying you if you win a contest). In addition, we may send you an email offering products or services that we think you may be interested in, or ask you to participate in a survey. We may also contact you offline (e.g., if you provide your mailing address, we may mail you special offers, promotions, and catalogs that we think may be of interest to you). We will seek to obtain your consent at the place where the information is collected either by an "opt-in" or "opt-out" method, or by other means (such as email). However, for shop customers only, we will seek to obtain your consent when we collect your personal information for the first time so that we can apply your preferences to future checkouts. If you want us to stop using the personal information you provided in these ways, please email us.
How We Share Your Personal Information.
We will not share with third parties the personal information you provide except (a) if it is for the purpose(s) you provided it; (b) with your consent; (c) as may be required by law or as we think necessary to protect our company or others from injury (e.g., in response to a court order or subpoena, in response to a law enforcement agency request, or when we believe that someone is causing (or about to cause) injury to or interference with the rights or property of another); (d) with other persons, service providers, or companies with whom we contract to carry out internal site operations or our business activities (e.g., sending out a product or a promotional item that you have requested on the Site); and/or (e) notifying you when we make material changes to one of our subscriber agreements or this policy. We will seek to obtain your consent at the place where the information is collected either by an "opt-in" or "opt-out" method, or by other means (such as email). However, for shop customers only, we will seek to obtain your consent when we collect your personal information for the first time so that we can apply your preferences to future checkouts.
If you would like to opt-out of receiving offline communications from us, please email us or let us know in writing via letter addressed to: Attn: Privacy Under the Nile, 14020 Forest Crest Dr, Chesterfield, MO 63017. For all postal mail opt-out requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We cannot accept opt-out requests via telephone or facsimile, nor will we be responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly or lack complete information. Please note that we may require up to sixty (60) days to fully remove your postal mail information from our mailings.
If we do share personal information with a non-affiliated company, to the extent practical, we require that they protect such information in a manner that is consistent with this policy. We cannot, however, guarantee how these non-affiliated companies will use your personal information. Following your opt-out, please be aware that our company or our affiliates may continue to contact you via email or postal mail for administrative or informational purposes, including, but not limited to, follow-up messages regarding the administration of your account, any services, features, or functions you have affirmatively enrolled in or registered to use, any promotions or sweepstakes you have participated in or have entered, goods, services, or products you have ordered, or other transactions you have undertaken on the Site.
Use and Disclosure of Anonymous Information.
We sometimes use the non-personal information that we collect to improve the design and content of the Site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze how the Site is used, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services. Sometimes we share aggregate information with others, including both affiliated and non-affiliated companies.
We may also allow third-party companies to serve advertisements and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit the Site. Such companies may use non-personal information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time, date, and/or subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Site and other websites in order to make available advertisements about goods and services that such information indicates would likely be of greater interest to you. Such companies typically use a cookie or third-party web beacons to collect this type of non-personal information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or how you may opt-out of these types of advertising, you can visit www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.
If you would prefer not to receive marketing or promotional emails from us that may relate, for example, to new services or offerings, or would like to edit your preferences, you may opt-out of receiving these communications.
Collection of Information By Others.
The Site may contain links to other websites, such as third-party advertisements or text hyperlinks. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any other website. We encourage all users of the Site to be aware of when they leave the Site, and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by the Site, through the Site. We may offer additional email services or promotions that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with non-affiliated companies. Based on our agreement with them, these third parties may obtain personal information that site visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. We have no control over the use of this information by these companies.
Cookies.
A cookie is a small file, which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We may set and use cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about our web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Clickstream Data.
As you use the Internet, a trail of electronic information is left at each web site you visit. This information, which is sometimes referred to as "Clickstream Data," can be collected and stored by a web site's server. Clickstream Data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the web site from which you linked to the Site. We may use Clickstream Data as a form of non-personal information to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of the Site, how visitors navigate throughout the Site, and how we may tailor our web pages to better meet the needs of visitors. This information will only be used to improve the Site. Any collection or use of Clickstream Data will be anonymous and aggregate.
Supplementing Information.
From time to time we may supplement information you give us with information from other sources, such as information validating your address. Thus, information we obtain through the Site may be intermingled with and used in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the Site, including both offline and online sources.
Our Commitment to Security.
We believe we have in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online. Whenever personal information is passed on to non-affiliated companies, to the extent practical, we require that they also have in place the appropriate safeguards. We cannot, however, guarantee that they do so.
California Privacy Policy.
Under the Nile collects various types of personal information about you during the course of our business relationship. If you are a California resident, you are entitled under California law to request a report detailing how we have shared your personal information during the prior calendar year with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. In response to your request, Under the Nile will provide you with a cost-free means to opt out of such sharing. For purposes of the California Privacy notice, third parties include companies within our “family”—those that we own, are owned by, and that are under a common ownership.
If you would like to exercise your rights under California law, please send your written request to the postal address below. We will provide you with a Customer Choice Notice within 30 (thirty) days.
Postal mail:Under the Nile, Privacy16141 Swingley Ridge Rd.Suite #106Chesterfield, MO 63017
Phone:(636) 778 - 3655(636) 778 - 3656(636) 778 - 3657(636) 778 - 3658 FAX ONLY
International Users.
If you are visiting the Site from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States, your orders placed through the Site will be fully processed in and shipped from the United States, and all information you provide will be processed and securely maintained in our web servers and internal systems located within the United States. IN ADDITION, IF YOU ARE LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES, YOU SHOULD NOTE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, THE LAWS OF WHICH MAY BE DEEMED BY OTHER COUNTRIES TO HAVE INADEQUATE DATA PROTECTION (e.g., see European Union Directive 95/46/EC of 24 October 1995). Users of the Site located in countries outside of the United States of America who submit personal information do thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to and/or storage of the information in the United States of America. This policy and our legal obligations are subject to the laws of the State of New York and the United States of America, regardless of the location of any user. Any claims or complaints must be filed in the United States of America in the State of New York.
How You Can Access or Correct Your Personal Information.
To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.
Transfer of Business Assets.
The personal information you provide is considered a company asset and may be included among transferred assets if the Site, Company, parent company, any or all of our subsidiaries or affiliates, or any of our assets are ever acquired by a third-party.
Changes to this Policy.
Because our business needs may change over time, we reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. If at any time in the future we plan to use your personal information in a way that differs from this policy, we will revise this policy as appropriate. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes. This policy is effective as of August 1, 2014.
How to Contact Us.
If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy you contact us as follows:
Under the Nile Privacy16141 Swingley Ridge Rd.Suite #106Chesterfield, MO 63017
Phone:636-778-3655
Email:
underthenile@underthenile.com
Hello You!
Join our mailing list
X
Shipping & Delivery
Domestic us Shipping, Free Over $49*
Shipping Method
Saver Shipping Post (up to 10 business days) Free Over $49*
$6.95
UPS Ground (1 to 5 business days )
$12.95
Expedited (Next business day)
Live rate, depends on address + weight
*Free shipping method is via USPS within the continental USA, excluding Alaska and HawaiiLarge items like rugs and blankets are exempt from free shipping.
For more information regarding PO boxes, Rural areas + International shipping, please click here.
Return policy
At Under the Nile we take pride in the high quality of all our products
If you are not completely satisfied with your purchase, we offer refunds or exchanges for the purchase price or store credit within 15 days of receipt.
Click here for more.
